

# **ROMAULI SIAGIAN**

Informatics Student

#### PERSONAL BACKGROUND

I am an udergraduate informatics students. I have experienced in manual and automated testing from web applications. i have a sprit in learning new knowledge and things, hardworking person comfortable working in teams, accept challenge, high responsibility, good communication skills that make me quickly adapt to new environments.

### **SKILLS**

### Testing

- -JUnit
- Cucumber
- Robot Framework
- -Selenium

#### QA

- SQA Process
- SDLC
- Black-box and White Box methodologies

### Web Development

- HTML5
- CSS
- -Java Script
- -PHP
- -Boostrap
- -Laravel

## Database

- -mySQL
- -SQLyog
- -PHPMyAdmin
- CSS

#### Design

- -Adobe XD
- -Fidgma
- -CorelDraw
- -UI/UX
- Photoshop

Programming: C, Java, Kotlin, Python

### **LANGUAGE**

- Indonesia (Excellent)
- English(Intermediate)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Lab Assistent | Institut Teknologi Del

### Fundamentals Physics I | Sept 2019 - Feb 2020

- Provide students with evidence to implement concepts and theories into practice.
- Conducting tests on student understanding before experimenting

### Fundamentals Physics II | Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Provide students with evidence to implement concepts and theories into practice.
- Conducting tests on student understanding before experimenting

# Tutorial Assistent | Institut Teknologi Del

### Discrete Mathematics | Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Provide students with an understanding of the basic concepts of discrete mathematics
- Make an evaluation with some conceptual question exercises
- Provide intensive guidance

### **ORGANIZATION**

### Tanoto Foundation Scholarship | 2018- present

- Help learning for elementary school students
- Invite people around Lake Toba to care about trash
- Receive leadership training and scholarships to program participants.

# Member of Departement Education of Informatics Students Association $[HIMASTI] \mid 2019$

- Provide understanding to students about the material that is not understood
- Help in the himasti mengajar program

### Committee of Progran Cinta Almamater | 2019

- Helping new students to adapt in the Del Institute of Technology

# Head of Departement Education of Informatics Students Association [HIMASTI], 2020

- Provide webinars for himasti members with alumni
- -Provide discussion to himasti members about material that is not understood

### PROJECT UNDERTAKEN

## Development of Web and Mobile based "Covid Checking" Application | Jan 2021 - Present

- Description: aims to find out the status of certain areas that have been visited by people who have tested positive for Covid-19
- -Tools: Cucumber, Robot, Manual Testing, Enclips IDE
- Role: QA and Tester

# MyLazyQuis Website Testing with ATDD and BDD | Sept 2020-

- Description: aims to help students in doing quizzes and management schedules during pjj
- -Tools: Doc SRS,Laravel, boostraps, Cucumber, Robot, Manuat Testing, Enclips IDE, sqlyog
- Role: Analysis, web development, QA and Tester

# MyLazyQuis Android Application Development | Sept 2020- Jan 2021

- Description: aims to help students in doing quizzes and management schedules during pjj
- -Tools: Doc SRS, Android Studio, Kotlin langunage
- Role: Analysis and QA

# **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Informatics Del | Institut of Technology 2018 Present
- Science Major |SMA N 1 Balige 2014-2017

### **PERSONAL**

- Adaptability
- Working with team
- Communication skill
- Leadership
- -Fast learner
- -Responsibility
- Project Management

### CONTACT

Phone: +6282167122173

Email: romaulisiagian45@gmail.com

Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/romauli-

siagian-4aa2a2184/

Address: Dolok Nabolon, Kec.Sigumpar, Kab.Toba

Samosir, Sumatera Utara, WhatsApp: +6282267524060

### Redesign Radio Del Application | Feb 2020- Jun 2020

-Description: Aims to redesign the Del FM application interface.

-Tools: Adobe XD

- Role: Analysis and UI/UX

### Library Application | Sept 2019- Jan 2020

- Description: This project aims to help users access the library application and help library admins to add books in the application using CRUD data
- Tools: Neatbins with java, MySQL, Visual Paradigma
- Role: Analysis and developer

### WildMild game | March 2019- May 2019

- Description: This project aims to make simple game and make a power generator from the wind using scratch
- Tools: Scratch
- Role: game Developer

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Graduate of C programming Masterclass for software Developers Online Course of Udemy 2019
- Graduate of Java programming Beginnerclass Online Course of Dicoding 2019
- Graduate of Path Pengembangan Web for coding Experience Bootcampt 2020 CFDS X Progate
- Graduation of introduction to data science with python DQLab, 2021
- Finalist of BRIHackathon 2021